Pitt Jazz Collection, 1971-2011 UA.90.8.26.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert, 1971-2011; I.
  - Participant Relations, 1971-2006; 6.
    - Contracts [RESTRICTED], 1971-2006
      - Max Roach [RESTRICTED], 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 133)
      - Sonny Rollins [RESTRICTED], 1974-1984 (Box 6, Folder 134)
      - Wallace Roney [RESTRICTED], 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 135)
      - Patrice Rushen [RESTRICTED], 1987-2000 (Box 6, Folder 136)
      - Joe Sample [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 6, Folder 137)
      - Arturo Sandoval [RESTRICTED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 138)
      - Michael Schiller [RESTRICTED], 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 139)
      - John Schreiber [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 140)
      - John Schofield [RESTRICTED], 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 141)
      - Don Sebesky [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Paul Silverthorn [RESTRICTED], 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 143)
      - Woody Shaw [RESTRICTED], 1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 144)
      - Carl Smith [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Box 6, Folder 145)
      - Lew Soloff [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 146)
      - The Sounds of Heritage [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 147)
      - Dakota Stanton [RESTRICTED], 1979 (Box 6, Folder 148)
      - Moses Stith [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 6, Folder 149)
      - Sonny Stitt [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 150)
      - Charles Subey [RESTRICTED], 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 151)
      - Akira Tana [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 6, Folder 152)
      - Billy Taylor [RESTRICTED], 1979 (Box 6, Folder 153)
      - Yvone Taylor [RESTRICTED], 1971 (Box 6, Folder 154)
      - Clark Terry [RESTRICTED], 1971-1998 (Box 6, Folder 155)
      - Toots Thielemans [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 156)
      - Paul Thompson [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 157)
      - Clifford Thornton [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 6, Folder 158)
      - Charles Tolliver [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 159)
      - Nestor Torres [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 160)
      - Stanley Turrentine [RESTRICTED], 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 161)
      - Miroslav Vitous [RESTRICTED], 1982-1992 (Box 6, Folder 162)
      - Freddie Waits [RESTRICTED], 1977-1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 163)
      - Cedar Walton [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 6, Folder 164)
      - Grover Washington Jr.[RESTRICTED], 1979-1999 (Box 6, Folder 165)
      - Ernie Watts [RESTRICTED], 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 166)
      - Bobby Watson [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 6, Folder 167)
      - The Waymonnaires [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 6, Folder 168)
      - Tom Wendt [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 169)
      - Mark Whitfield [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 170)
      - Ernie Wilkins [RESTRICTED], 1971 (Box 6, Folder 171)
      - Marvin Witofsky [RESTRICTED], 1996 (Box 6, Folder 172)
      - Phillip Woo [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Box 6, Folder 173)
      - Attila Zoller [RESTRICTED], 1979 (Box 6, Folder 174)
      - General [RESTRICTED], 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 175)
      - Jazz Seminar Think Tank [RESTRICTED], 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Biographical Information, 1971-2006
      - Participant List, Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert, 1971-2006 (Box 1, Folder 74)
      - Michelle Adams, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - Monty Alexander, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      - Geri Allen, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - Alpha, 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Komla Amoaku, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Benny Bailey, 1981-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - David Baker, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Kenny Barron, 1980-1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - John Blake, ca. 1971-2011 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Art Blakey, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - Terrence Blanchard, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Oscar Brashear, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Randy Brecker, 1985-2007 (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - George Butler, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Donald Byrd, 1971-2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Terri Lynne Carrington, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Ron Carter, ca. 1971-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Philip Catherine, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - Joe Chambers, ca. 1971-2011 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - David Chertok, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Billy Cobham, 1988-2003 (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - William Cole, 1976-1996 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Larry Coryell, 1976-2008 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Richard Davis, 1971-1979 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Alan Dawson, 1971*-1991 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Ray Drummond, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Billy Eckstine, 1989-1992 (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - Kevin Eubanks, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Jon Faddis, 1986-1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Art Farmer, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 32)
      - Leonard Feather, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Clare Fischer, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - Charles Fishman, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Boo Frazier, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Curtis Fuller, 1993-2002 (Box 29, Folder 34)
      - Ira Gitler, 1978-2003 (Box 29, Folder 35)
      - Benny Golson, 1993-2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Johnny Griffin, 1983-1996 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Jim Hall, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Slide Hampton, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Winard Harper, 1997-2006 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Lou Hayes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Percy Heath, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 36)
      - Terumasa Hino, 1978-1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Freddie Hubbard, 1984-2000 (Box 29, Folder 37)
      - Milton Jackson, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Suzan Jenkins, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 38)
      - Niranjan Jhaveri, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Elvin Jones, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Helen Keane, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 39)
      - Lee Konitz, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Abraham Laboriel, 1976-2007 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Dave Laing, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Russell Malone, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Herbie Mann, 1986-1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Ellis Marsalis, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Pat Martino, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 40)
      - Jackie McLean, 1997-2003 (Box 29, Folder 41)
      - Charles McPherson, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 42)
      - Mulgrew Miller, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Thelonious Monk, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Marcio Montarroyos, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - James Moody, 1972-2003 (Box 29, Folder 43)
      - Dan Morgenstern, 1971-2006 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Michael Mossman, 1987-2008 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - George Mraz, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 44)
      - Idris Muhammad, 1979-1998 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Joe Newman, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Dionizy Piatkowski, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 45)
      - Sonny Rollins, 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Wallace Roney (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Patrice Rusheen, 1987-2000 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Jimmy Owens, 1979-2006 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Arturo Sandoval, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - John Schrieber, 1983-2003 (Box 29, Folder 46)
      - Paul Silverthorn, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Lew Soloff, 1975-2004 (Box 29, Folder 47)
      - Billy Taylor, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Clark Terry, 1971-1998 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Toots Thielemans, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Charles Tolliver, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Stanley Turrentine, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Grover Washington Jr, 1979-1999 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - The Waymonaries, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Annie Whitehead, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 48)
      - Marvin Witofsky, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Atilla Zoller, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Jazz Seminar Transcripts, 1984-1987; 8.
    - Transcript: "The Situation of the Musicians in the European Radio and Television Stations" with Elias Gistelinck, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Music Synthesis with Randy Brecker, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: "Market Your Talent" with George Butler and Harry Connick Jr., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Saxophone with George Coleman, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Bass with Ray Drummond, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Trumpet Workshop Jon Faddis, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Bass with Abraham Laboriel, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Flute with Herbie Mann, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Jazz Critics, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Trumpet with Mike Mossman, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Trumpet and Stage Rehearsal Techniques with Jimmy Owens and Stage Band, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Piano with Patrice Rushen, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Piano with Joe Sample, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Guitar with John Scofield, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Drums with Marvin 'Smitty' Smith, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Bicentennial Seminar Transcript: Drums with Akira Tana, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Bicentennial Seminar: Saxophone Workshop with Grover Washington Jr., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Jimmy Owens Correspondence and Jazz Seminar Transcription, 1987, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - George Coleman Jazz Seminar Tapes Transcription, 1989, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 55)
- International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame, 1977-1999; II.
  This series is divided into three subseries, Formation, Hall of Fame Induction, and Exhibit Planning. The series contains correspondence that illustrates how the Hall of Fame came to be, nominations and voting results for hall of fame inductees, correspondence with jazz artists regarding artifact donation and plans for the construction of the hall of fame display at the William Pitt Union. The files in this series are arranged thematically and chronically within their subseries. Further, artifacts and material displayed and contained in the International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame display case in the William Pitt Union from 1986-2016 are now housed at the Archives Service Center.
  - Formation, 1979-1984; 1.
    - Formally Establishing the International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame Dedication Ceremony, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Hall of Fame Induction, 1977-2003; 2.
    - Nomination and Voting Committee, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Induction Notes, 1975-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Inductee List, 1978-2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Voting, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Nominations and Voting, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Nominations, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Nominations, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Nominations, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Nominations, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Nominations, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Nominations, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Nominations, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Nominations, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Nominations, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Nominations, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Inductee Correspondence, 1984-2002 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1980-2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Press, 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Exhibit Planning, 1983-1986; 3.
    - Plaque Design and Installation, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 26-29)
    - Display Case Blueprints, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Inductee Artifact Donation, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Artifact Inventory and Appraisal, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Bronze Plaque Sketches, undated (Box 29, Folder 90)
    - A Strategic Business Plan, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Exhibit Donations, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Display Case Blueprints, undated (Box 29, Tube 1-2)
  - Jazz Hall of Fame Meeting Minutes, undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Jazz Hall of Fame Plaques, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Jazz Hall of Fame Brochure, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Finances and meeting minutes, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Hall of Fame Award, Dizzy Gillespie, 1989-1992 (Box 29, Folder 9)
- International Jazz Archives Journal, 1992-2001; III.
  This series has been divided into four subseries, Organization, Editorial Correspondence, Article Drafts, and Press and Related Publications. The Editorial Correspondence files have been filed by year and arranged chronologically. Similarly the Article Drafts have been filed by journal volume and number and arranged chronologically.
  - Organization, 1994-1999; 1.
    - Finances, 1994-1999 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Board of Editors, undated (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Journal Authors, 1994-1998 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Editorial Correspondence, 1992-2001; 2.
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Editorial Correspondence, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Peter Hollerbach Correspondence and Abstract, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - Geri Allen Correspondence, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Joe Viera Correspondence, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - Robert Sacré Correspondence, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - François-Xavier Moulé Correspondence and Photos, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - André Hodier Correspondence and Music, 1994-1995 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Article Drafts, 1994-1999; 3.
    - Volume 1. Number 2, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - Volume 1. Number 4, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 48-49)
    - Volume 2. Number 1, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 50-51)
    - Volume 2. Number 2, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 52-54)
    - Volume 1. Number 3, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 56)
  - Press and Related Publications, 1994-1998; 4.
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - International Jazz Archive Journal Newsletter, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - Review of Melton Mustafa's "The Creative Spirit of Clifford Brown", 1998 (Box 29, Folder 57)
- Jazz Studies, 1986-2001; IV.
  This series contains Jazz Studies curriculum information, materials related to the planning, promotion and application process for the Pitt-Mellon Scholarship, and the construction of the William R. Robinson Recording Studio. The series also contains over 20 years of jazz ensemble records including the constitution and student organization information, materials related to a number of tours the ensemble took part in, as well as local performances. The files in this series have been arranged chronologically within their respective subseries.
  - Academic Programs and Scholarships, 1986-1998; 2.
    - Curriculum, 1977-1998 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Pitt Mellon Jazz Scholarship, Internal Communication, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Pitt-Mellon Jazz Scholarship Promotional Material, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Pitt-Mellon Jazz Scholarship, Judge Correspondence, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - William R. Robinson Recording Studio, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Pitt Mellon Jazz Scholarship Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - International Academy of Jazz African-American Music Program, 2000 (Box 52, Folder 54)
    - International Academy of Jazz African-American Music Program, 2002-2003 (Box 52, Folder 55)
    - International Academy of Jazz African-American Music Program, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 56)
    - International Academy of Jazz African-American Music Program, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 57)
    - Nathan Davis Mentor Program, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 86)
    - Undergraduate Exchange Program, 1974-1989 (Box 52, Folder 89)
  - Jazz Ensemble, 1978-2000; 3.
    - Constitution and Student Organization Materials, 1983-1994 (Box 52, Folder 66)
    - New Orleans Concert Tour, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 67)
    - Trinidad and Tobago Concert Tour, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 68)
    - Caribbean Concert Tour, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 69)
    - Jamaica Concert Tour, 1988-1990 (Box 52, Folder 70)
    - Jamaica Concert Tour, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 71)
    - General Concert Tour Materials, 1980-1982 (Box 52, Folder 72)
    - Jazz Corner with Machito Cuban Jazz Ensemble, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 73)
    - Brown Bag Lunch Series, 1998-1999 (Box 52, Folder 74)
    - Spring Concert Materials, 1997-1999 (Box 52, Folder 75)
    - Promotional and Press, 1978-2000 (Box 52, Folder 76)
    - Contracts [RESTRICTED], 1986-1994 (Box 52, Folder 77)
    - Jamaica Concert Tour, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 91)
    - Jamaica Concert Tour, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 92)
    - Jamaica Concert Tour, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 93)
    - Jamaica Concert Tour, 2009 (Box 29, Folder 94)
    - Ensemble Brown Bag [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - University of Pittsburgh Headlines, Office of Public Affairs, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - James Moody Concert [RESTRICTED], 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Finances, Spring Jazz Ensemble [RESTRICTED], April 2003 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Finances, Spring Jazz Ensemble [RESTRICTED], April 2004 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Jazz Ensemble Students, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Jazz Ensemble Auditions Flyer, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Jazz Ensemble Auditions Flyer, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Jazz Seminar Outreach Program-Dubai, 2003-2006 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Jazz Archives, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Allegheny City Council Proclamation, 2010 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Nathan Davis, 1973-2001; V.
  Biography
  Dr. Nathan Davis was born in Kansas City, Missouri, in 1937. He holds a PhD in Ethnomusicology from Wesleyan University. Prior to becoming the director of Jazz Studies at the University of Pittsburgh in 1969, Davis spent a number of years as part of the expatriate jazz scene. Davis is the author of Writings in Jazz, African-American Music in Society as well as a handful of other publications. In addition to writing and his departmental responsibilities, Dr. Davis has worked for decades as a celebrated tenor and soprano saxophonist. Davis has composed and recorded numerous musical pieces including the 2004 jazz opera, "Just Above My Head," based on the novel of the same name written by James Baldwin.
  The following series is not a comprehensive representation of Dr. Davis, but contains records related to a number of his activities during his time at the University of Pittsburgh. The series contains thirty years of correspondence, drafts of his book African American Music. The series also contains a number of topical files including a small collection of Dr. Davis' press, jazz artists, and local jazz festivals.
  - Correspondence, 1970-2000; 1.
    - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 30, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 30, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 79)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 80)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 81-82)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Publishing, ca. 1996, undated; 2.
    - Original Draft: African American Music, ca. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6-10)
    - Second Draft: African American Music, ca. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11-15)
    - Final Draft: African American Music, ca. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
    - "Jazz-A Return to the Roots", undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Permissions,University of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar Photo Album, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence and Permissions,Writings in Jazz (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Review, The University of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar Photo Album, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "Writings in Jazz," Third Edition, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - "Writings in Jazz" Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 29, Folder 70)
    - "Writings in Jazz", 1976 (Box 29, Folder 71)
    - "Writings in Jazz," Third Edition, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 72)
    - "The Quintessential Blues: A Jazz Portrait", undated (Box 29, Folder 73)
    - "Jazz-Afro-American Music in the University", undated (Box 29, Folder 74)
    - Pitt Magazine, Against the Grain: Sculptor Thaddeus Mosely Carves His Own Career, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 75)
    - Pitt Magazine, Jazz: Where the Stars Teach, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 76)
    - Pitt Magazine, Mind Control, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 77)
    - Carnegie Magazine, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 78)
  - Topical Files, 1973-2000; 4.
    - Testimonial Dinner, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - News Clippings, 1970-2004 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Write-ups, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Interview with Joe Sanford conducted by David S. Miller, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - "A Jazz Happening at Pitt" by Sherry Miller Brown, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - "Towards a Definition of Soul", undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - "Stylistic Change in Jazz: 1945-1962", undated (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Artists: Theo Avery, undated (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Artists: Margie Balter, undated (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Artists: Bill Cole, undated (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Artists: Talmage Farlow, undated (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Artists: Vijay Iyer, undated (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Artist: Helen Keane, undated (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Artist: Eric Marienthal, undated (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Artists: Jim McNeely, undated (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Artists: Queen Bey, undated (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Pittsburgh Kool Jazz Festival, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Pittsburgh Jazz Festival Programs, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Manchester Craftsmen's Guild, 1991-1993 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Jazz Yatra '96, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Jazz Magazine, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Pitt Magazine, Portrait of an Artist- Geri Allen emerges as a New Sound in Jazz, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - News Clippings, 1996-1998 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Carmell William Jones Jr., 1996 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - The Roots, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 44)
    - Nathan Davis Performances and Appearances, undated (Box 52, Folder 45)
    - Pittsburgh Jazz Orchestra, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 46)
    - Tomorrow International, Inc., undated (Box 52, Folder 47)
    - Mellon Jazz Festival, Promotional Material, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 50)
    - Mellon Jazz Festival Newspaper Clippings, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 51)
    - Composition in Africa and the Diaspora, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 79)
    - Pittsburgh Kool Jazz Festival, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 80)
    - 3rd International Symposium and Festival, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 81)
    - Awards and Honors, 1978-2006 (Box 29, Folder 82)
    - Mellon Jazz Festival Student Jazz Spectacular, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 83)
    - Mary Lou Williams' Jazz Mass, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 84)
    - Kiddafest Jazz Festival, Ghana, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 85)
    - Nathan Davis Membership Dues, 2003-2004 (Box 29, Folder 86)
    - Cambridge Program, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 87)
    - Nathan Davis Biography, 1991-1995 (Box 29, Folder 88)
    - International Academy of Jazz/African American Music Program, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 95)
    - Paris Reunion Band, 1985-1986 (Box 29, Folder 96)
    - Strong Men and Women: The Series, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 98)
    - UNESCO, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 99)
    - Pittsburgh Magazine Cover, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Bahia, Brazil Jazz Festival, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 101)
    - Bahia, Brazil Jazz Festival [RESTRICTED], 2000 (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Bahia, Brazil Jazz Festival [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Bahia, Brazil Jazz Festival, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Steelband Music Festival, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Brazilian Sheet Music, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Cultural Engineering, Dubai, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Jazz Middelheim Festival, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Compositions